## **Manuel Palacios**

Senior Manager of Product Quality Engineering

# Summary

Accomplished engineering leader in quality, reliability, failure analysis, process development and manufacturing for electronic computing products (both enterprise and consumer application). Able to build highly motivated technical teams focused on achieving aggressive goals. Excellent verbal and written communication skills

Mechanical Engineer with strong technical background in Design for Quality/Reliability, Materials Science and Advanced Data Analysis. Proven management experience of more than 15 years in the semiconductor, electronics components, computing and consumer electronic industries. Led large engineering global teams.

# Experience

#### Senior Product Quality Engineering Manager at Google

June 2015 - Present

#### Senior Manager of Product Quality Engineering at Amazon Lab126

November 2011 - June 2015 (3 years 8 months)

Led Product Quality Engineering organization for Lab126 Amazon's elite product development organization. Successfully delivered Quality improvement by influencing Design, Material and Manufacturing decisions early during development for multiple generations of Amazon E-Readers, Tablets, Audio Cloud Computers & Streaming Media Products (under Kindle, Fire, Dash & Echo brands).

#### Corporate Quality & Reliability Manager at Gennum Corp

September 2006 - December 2011 (5 years 4 months)

Directed the Corporate Quality, Reliability and Failure Analysis Department for Gennum Corporation (now part of Semtech), responsible for the definition and execution of quality and reliability qualification for new products as well as quality continuous improvement and supplier quality management for Professional Products on Commercial Video, Datacom, Computing and Audio markets in high volume manufacturing

#### Quality, Reliability and Failure Analysis Engineering Manager at Intel Corp

June 1997 - September 2006 (9 years 4 months)

Managed Quality & Reliability departments for Intel's most advanced Components, Systems and Wafer fabrication factories. Responsibilities included management of failure analysis, quality management systems, process qualification, control and improvement for high volume production. Led a staff of more than 55 Engineer and Managers. Also managed areas of Product/Test Engineering.

#### Senior Process Development Engineer at Motorola Corp

January 1995 - July 1997 (2 years 7 months)

## **Quality Test Engineer**

1994 - 1995 (2 years)

## Education

## Universidad de Costa Rica

Bachelor, Mechanical Engineering, 1989 - 1994

#### **Universidad Alma Mater**

Master of Business Administration - MBA, International Business/Trade/Commerce

# **Manuel Palacios**

Senior Manager of Product Quality Engineering



Contact Manuel on LinkedIn